Guide to the Mobilization for Youth Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Mobilization for Youth Records,
[ca. 1958]-1970.
Mobilization for Youth.
ca. 10, 500 items (29 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079120
Historical Note
Social service agency operating on the Lower East Side of New York City. Mobilization for Youth was conceived in 1957 and formally founded and funded in 1961.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, minutes, memoranda, reports, project proposals, financial records, and related printed materials documenting various social services focused on community development, the elimination of poverty, and the prevention and control of juvenile deliquency. Among its programs are manpower and training services such as the Neighborhood Youth Corps, a remedial education and work program, and the New Careers Program, providing both instruction and on the job training; individual, group, and family services such as counseling and supportive services for jovenile delinquents; and mental health services. The correspondence is with city, state, and federal agencies as well as private social service organizations. Correspondents include John V. Lindsay. Also, files for Bertram M. Beck, Executive Director, the Board of Directors, the various committees, and project funding activities.
Subjects
Neighborhood Youth Corps (U.S.); Lindsay, John V. (John Vliet); Beck, Bertram M.; New York (N.Y.)--Social conditions.; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.)--Social conditions.; New Careers Program.; Social work with youth--New York (State)--New York.; Social work with criminals--New York (State)--New York.; Family social work--New York (State)--New York.; Family services--New York (State)--New York.; Mental health services--New York (State)--New York.; Community development--New York (State)--New York.; Poverty.; Juvenile delinquency--New York (State)--New York.; Manpower--New York (State)--New York.; Remedial teaching--New York (State)--New York.; Public welfare--New York (State)--New York.; Charities--New York (State)--New York.; Social service--New York (State)--New York.
Access Restrictions
Boxes 2-27 of this collection are located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1979 M-79 Mobilization for Youth via Social Work Library Gift
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Herman Badillo (Box 1)
  - Helen Hall (Box 1)
  - John V. Lindsay (Box 1)
  - Newbold Morris (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1963 -1970 (Box 1)
- Series II: Office Files
  - Administrative Committee of the Board of Directors -9/65 -5/66 (Box 2)
  - Adult Employment and Small Business Demonstrations (Box 2)
  - Adventure Corps (Box 2)
  - The Annotated Bibliography, February 1964 (Box 2)
  - Arts Center Committee of Henry Street Settlement House (Box 2)
  - Association of Community Service Centers (Box 2)
  - Beck, Bertram M. -Biographical Information (Box 2)
  - Beck, Bertram M. -Correspondence (Congratulatory letters on MFY appointment) (Box 2)
  - Beck, Bertram M. -Ego Support: MFY appointment (four Folders) (Box 2)
  - Applications for Demonstration or Training Grants (Box 2)
  - Board of Directors -12 June 1962 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -10 April 1963 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -23 February -April 1965 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -4 May 1965 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -11 June 1965 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -1 July 1965 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -22 July 1965 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -13 October 1965 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -10 November 1965 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -12 January 1966 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -9 February 1966 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -9 March 1966 (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors -4 May 1966 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -6 October 1966 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -3 November 1966 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -1 December 1966 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -21 December 1966 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -2 February 1967 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -9 March 1967 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -6 April 1967 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -17 May 1967 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -29 June 1967 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -1 November 1967 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -1969 -1970 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors -Board Committees (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors -By-laws (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors –Correspondence, 1965 -1966 (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors. –Correspondence, 1966 -1967 (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors –Correspondence, 1967 -1968 (Box 5)
  - Board of' Directors -Correspondence with Chairmen, 1965 -1966 (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors -Correspondence with Chairmen, 1966 -1967 (Box 5)
  - Board of' Directors -Correspondence: Meeting Schedule, 1966 -1967 (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors -t1ailing List (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors -Membership List (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors Membership List (Potential) (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors -Membership with MFY and other affiliations (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors -Nominating Committee (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors Nominating Committee: Correspondence (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors -Pending (Box 5)
  - Board of Directors Reorganization of Membership (Box 6)
  - Board of Directors -Residences of Membership (Box 6)
  - Board of Directors -Resignations I Board of Directors -Resolution (Box 6)
  - Board of Trustees -First Meeting, 24 October 1958 (Box 6)
  - Board of Trustees -Membership List (Box 6)
  - Board of Trustees -Memoranda (Box 6)
  - Brager, George re: Resignation (Box 6)
  - Budget -Program and Staff Development Administration I Budget -Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Budget -Proposals: 1964 -1966 (Box 6)
  - Budget -Proposals: 1966 -1967 (Box 6)
  - Budgeting (Box 6)
  - By-laws (Box 6)
  - Certificate of Incorporation -MFY (Box 6)
  - Chart -Fund Requested 1967 (Box 6)
  - Chart -Sviridoff Proposal (Box 6)
  - Children’s' Bureau (Box 6)
  - Citizens' Committee for Children (Box 6)
  - Clippings and Editorials Favorable to :.IFY 11/64 (Box 6)
  - Cognitive Dysfunction (Box 6)
  - Committee on Administration: Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Committee on Administration: Minutes 1965 -1966 (Box 6)
  - Committee on Administration: Hnu Committeetes 1966 -1967 (Box 6)
  - Committee on Administration: Orientation Materials (Box 6)
  - Committee on Administration: Subcommittee on Internal Audit (Box 6)
  - Committee on Administration: Subcommittee on Personnel Practices (Box 6)
  - Committee on Community Development: General (Box 7)
  - Committee on Community Development: Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Committee on Community Development: Meetings (Box 7)
  - Committee on Community Development: Orientation Materials (Box 7)
  - Committee on Community Development: Special Committee on Housing (Box 7)
  - Committee on Educational Opportunities: Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Committee on Educational Opportunities: Meetings 1965 -1966 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Educational Opportunities: Meetings 1966 -1967 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Educational Opportunities: l:>finutes (Box 7)
  - Committee on Educational Opportunities: Orientation Materials (Box 7)
  - Committee on Employment Opportunities: General (Box 7)
  - Committee on Employment Opportunities: Correspondence (Box 7)
  - Committee on Employment Opportunities: Meetings 1965 -1966 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Employment Opportunities: Meetings 1966 -1967 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Employment Opportunities: Membership (Box 7)
  - Committee on Employment; Opportunities: Orientation Materials (Box 7)
  - Committee on Individual, Group and Family Services: General Materials (Box 8)
  - Committee on Individual, Group and Family Services: Correspondence (Box 8)
  - Committee on Individual, Group and Family Services: Meetings 1966 (Box 8)
  - Committee on Individual, Group and Family Services: Orientation Materials (Box 8)
  - Committee on Legal Services: Correspondence (Box 8)
  - Committee on Legal Services: Meetings (Box 8)
  - Committee on Legal Services: Memoranda (Box 8)
  - Committee on Legal Services: Orientation Materials (Box 8)
  - Committee on Neighborhood Service Centers, Lower East Side (Box 8)
  - Committee on Study and Evaluation: Correspondence (Box 8)
  - Committee on Study and Evaluation: Meetings (Box 8)
  - Committee on Study and Evaluation: Report and evaluation (Box 8)
  - Community Action Program (three Folders) (Box 8)
  - Community Education Project (Box 9)
  - Community Mental Health Center (Box 9)
  - Community Service Center (Box 9)
  - Computer Training (Box 9)
  - Consumer Education and Action Program (Box 9)
  - Contract between Human Resources Administration and Mobilization for Youth: (Box 9)
  - Community Employment Technician Proposal (Box 9)
  - Contract between Human Resources Administration and Mobilization for Youth: (Box 9)
  - Developing New York City Manpower Services (Box 9)
  - Contract between New York City Economic Opportunity Committee and Mobilization for Youth (Box 9)
  - Crêche Nursery (Early Childhood Center) (Box 9)
  - Cultural Arts Center (Box 9)
  - Cultural Arts Program (Box 9)
  - Cultural Arts and Education (Box 9)
  - Cultural Education Project (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Center -Proposal and Progress Report (Box 9)
  - Demonstration for Upgrading Vocational Skills (Box 9)
  - Demonstration Leading to a Lower East Side Economic Development Project (Box 9)
  - Demonstration Project -Post-secondary Educational Opportunities (Box 9)
  - Department of Health, Education and Welfare -General (Box 9)
  - Department of Health, Education and Welfare -Grants (Box 9A)
  - Department of Labor -Consumer Prices (Box 9A)
  - Division of Educational Opportunities -General (Box 9A)
  - Division of Educational Opportunities -CUNY Proposal (Box 9A)
  - Division of Employment Opportunities -Martine Training Placing Situation (Box 9A)
  - Dolci, Danilo -Correspondence with Bertram Beck 1965 (Box 9A)
  - Dolci, Danilo -Committee: Educational Materials (two Folders) (Box 9A)
  - Dolci, Danilo -Committee: Fund Raising (Box 10)
  - Dolci, Danilo -Committee: Minutes of r-1eetings (Box 10)
  - Dolci, Danilo -Committee: Pending (Box 10)
  - Dolci, Danilo -Committee: Recruitment of Personnel (Box 10)
  - Dolci, Danilo -Committee: Tax Exemption (Box 10)
  - "Down East" Records (Box 10)
  - Economic Development (two Folders) (Box 10)
  - Economic Development Administration (Box 10)
  - Economic Development Program (Box 10)
  - Economy -Lower East Side (Box 10)
  - Educational -Vocational Resource Center (Box 10)
  - Elementary Reading Clinic -Experimental Reading Program (Box 10)
  - Emergency Family Loan Programs (Box 10)
  - Executive Committee: Correspondence (Box 11)
  - Executive Committee: Meeting 13 March 1963 (Box 11)
  - Executive Committee: Meetings 9/65 -5/67 (Box 11)
  - Executive Committee: Memoranda 9/65 -3/66 (Box 11)
  - Executive Staff Report 8/62 _ 6/65 (Box 11)
  - Executive Structure Resolution 14 September 1964 (Box 11)
  - Expenditures (Box 11)
  - Experimental Reading Program (Box 11)
  - Experimental Theatre Arts (Box 11)
  - Family Day Care (Box 11)
  - Ferris State College (Box 11)
  - Financial Reports 1 July 1963 -30 June "1964 (Box 11)
  - Financial Statements 30 June 1965 (Box 11)
  - Financing Program: Fiscal Year 1968 (Box 11)
  - Funding: General (two Folders) (Box 11)
  - Funding: Board of Education (Box 11)
  - Funding: Community Development Agency (Box 11)
  - Funding: Community Development Agency -Cultural Arts (Box 11)
  - Funding: Department of Health, Education and Welfare (Box 11)
  - Funding: Department of Labor (Box 11)
  - Funding: Economic Opportunity Committee (Box 12)
  - Funding: Ford Foundation (Box 12)
  - Funding: Human Resources Administration -General (four Folders) (Box 12)
  - Funding: HRA -Amelioration of Social Problems (Box 12)
  - Funding: HRA -Budget (Box 12)
  - Funding: Community Corporations (Box 12)
  - Funding: Community Development Agency (four Folders) (Box 12)
  - Funding: HRA - CDA Budget Questionnaires (Box 12)
  - Funding: HRA – CDA Medical (Box 13)
  - Funding: HRA – CDA New York Training Institute (Box 13)
  - Funding: HRA – CDA Vouchers (Box 13)
  - Funding: HRA Neighborhood Manpower Service Center (Box 13)
  - Funding: HRA Technical Assistants and Personnel (Box 13)
  - Funding: HRA MFY Contract (Box 13)
  - Funding: National Institute of Mental Health (Box 13)
  - Funding: Neighborhood Youth Corps. (Box 13)
  - Funding: Office of Economic Opportunity (two Folders) (Box 13)
  - Funding: OEO – Community Education Project (Box 13)
  - Funding: Requests 1966-1967 (Box 13)
  - Funding: OEO – Work Program (Box 13)
  - Girls’ Vocational Training Center (Box 14)
  - Guaranteed Annual Income – Correspondence (Box 14)
  - Guaranteed Annual Income – Drafts 1-4 (Box 14)
  - Haberman, Philip – Report re. MFY 25 November 1964 (Box 14)
  - Henry Street Settlement House – General (Box 14)
  - Henry Street Settlement House and MFY: Possible coordination (Box 14)
  - HEP News (Box 14)
  - Higher Education of Socially and Educationally Restricted Youth (Box 14)
  - Housing Reconditioning Project (Box 14)
  - Housing Rehabilitation and Economic Enhancement of the Poor (Box 14)
  - Individaul, Gamily and Group Services (Box 15)
  - Institute for research on Poverty – University of Wisconsin (Box 15)
  - Legal Services Unit - &A Corporation (Box 15)
  - Letter from Howard G. Janover to Board of Directors – 29 October 1964 (Box 15)
  - Letter from S.D. Leidesdorf and Company – Manual of Stabdard Procedures (Box 15)
  - Letters from Anne M. Roberts, Anti-poverty Operations Board (Box 15)
  - Lower East Side Employment Offices (Box 15)
  - Lower Manhattan Community Mental Heath Center (Box 15)
  - Manpower and Career Development Agency (Box 15)
  - Karate School (Box 15)
  - Meeting Notices (Box 15)
  - Memoranda: n.d.; 1961 -1969 (four Folders') (Box 15)
  - Memoranda to Staff (Box 15)
  - Memoranda: Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Minutes: 19 November 1958 -1 December 1958 -Board of Trustees (Box 16)
  - Minutes! 7 May 1959 -Board of Trustees (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 28 July 1959 -Board of Trustees (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 29 January 1960 -Nominating Committee (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 6 August 1962 -Board of Directors (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 10 October 1962 -Board of Directors (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 5 November 1962 -Contract Review Committee (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 3 December 1962 -Contract Review Committee (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 14 November 1962 -Executive Committee (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 3 -4 January 1963 -Citizens' Advisory Council (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 6 May 1963 -Contract Review Committee (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 11 June 1963 -Contract Review Committee (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 13 March 1963 -Executive Committee (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 25 February 1963 -Public Advisory Committee (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 23 January 1963 -Public Information Committee (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 15 April 1963 -Washington (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 17,20,24, 25 August 1964 -Board of Directors (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 4 November 1964 Board of Directors (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 19 November 1964 -Board of Directors (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 2 December 1964 -Board of Directors (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 30 December 1964 -Board of Directors (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 14 September 1964 -Board of Directors Executive Session (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 15 October 1964 "Board of Directors Executive Session (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 15 October 1964 -Committee of Fifteen (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 16 November 1964 -Executive Committee (Box 16)
  - Minutes: 14 January 1965 - Board of Directors (Box 17)
  - Minutes: 21 January 1965 – Board of Directors (Box 17)
  - Minutes: 1 February 1965 -Board of Directors (Box 17)
  - Minutes: 31 March -11 May 1966 -Board of Directors (Box 17)
  - Minutes: October 1965 -Committee on Employment Opportunities (Box 17)
  - Minutes: October 1965 -Committee on Study and Evaluation (Box 17)
  - Minutes: 9 March 1966 -Board of Directors (Box 17)
  - Minutes: 8 June 1966 -Board of Directors (Box 17)
  - Minutes: 3 November 1966 -Board of Directors (Box 17)
  - Minutes: 13 June 1961 -Ad Hoc Subcommittee on Port of Entry Helping Stations (Box 17)
  - Minutes: 11 May 1961 -Board of Directors (Box 17)
  - Minutes: 11 Hay 1961 -Legal Services Unit, Board of Advisors (Box 17)
  - Minutes: 17 June 1910 -Board of Directors (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Finance (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Minutes (unsorted) (Box 17)
  - Mobilization for Urban Action (Box 17)
  - Mobilization for Youth and Anti-poverty Program (Box 17)
  - Mobilization for Youth, - Future (Box 17)
  - Mobilization for Youth - Opportunities Development Program (Box 17)
  - Mobilization for Youth - Presentation 15 December 1959 (Box 17)
  - Mobilization for Youth Program Units - Family Subsidy Plan (Box 18)
  - Mobilization for Youth Remedial Education Program (Box 18)
  - Mobilization for Youth Program Units – Lower East Side Narcotics Unit (Box 18)
  - Mobilization for Youth Programs, 1966-1967 (Box 18)
  - Mobilization for Youth Programs, 1969 (Box 18)
  - Mobilization for Youth Reading Program, 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - Mobilization for Youth Skills Training Center (Box 18)
  - Mobilization for Youth Staff Newsletter (Box 18)
  - Mobilization for Youth Synopsis: Full Description of Division of Educational Opportunities (Box 18)
  - Mobilization for Youth Synopsis: Full Description Housing Department Report (Box 18)
  - Mobilization for Youth Synopsis: Full Description Neighborhood Service Centers – Services to Individuals and Families (Box 18)
  - National Alliance of Businessmen – JOBS Training Program (Box 18)
  - National Institute of Mental Health – Application for Public Health Service Grant or Award (Box 18)
  - National Institute of Mental Health – Second Grade Program (Box 18)
  - Neighborhood Education Center (Box 18)
  - Neighborhood Manpower Centers (Box 18)
  - Neighborhood Service center (Box 18)
  - Neighborhood Youth Corps. (Box 18)
  - New Careers Action Laboratory (Box 19)
  - New Careers Action Laboratory (Box 19)
  - New York City South Board (Box 19)
  - New York Training Institute (two Folders plus one binder) (Box 19)
  - New York Urban Coalition – General (Box 19)
  - New York Urban Coalition – Employee Relations Assistant (Box 19)
  - New York Urban Coalition Manpower Task Force (Box 19)
  - Occupational Shortages and Surpluses – October 1969 (Box 19)
  - Office of Economic Opportunity – Grants (Box 19)
  - Office of Economic Opportunity – Economic Development (Box 19)
  - Operational Studies (Box 19)
  - Panel Discussion on Functional Systems (Box 19)
  - Panel of Experts Report on MFY, 18 November 1964 (Box 19)
  - Personnel Practice Committee, 8 March 1963 (Box 19)
  - Personnel Practice Committee, 13 July 1963 (Box 19)
  - Planningh Conference for a National Council on New Careers, December 1967 (Box 19)
  - Plans for Educational Program, 1965-1966 (Box 19)
  - Police -Community Relations (Box 20)
  - Policy Management Systems (Box 20)
  - Postal Cards -Committee Meetings (Box 20)
  - Presentation Meeting -2 Feb 1959 (Box 20)
  - Professional Resumes (Box 20)
  - Program of Individual Services (Box 20)
  - Program of Services to Low-income Businessmen (Box 20)
  - Program Reporting (Curriculum Center) -Draft and Final (Box 20)
  - Project 914 -Brooks Foundation (Box 20)
  - Proposals -Three unarranged Folders (Box 20)
  - Proposal: Adult Employment Program (Box 20)
  - Proposal: Block Associations (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Block Organizing Unit (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Child Care Center. (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Community Organization Unit for Short-Term Social Action (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Community Program in Consumer Affairs (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Consumer Affairs Program (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Data Processing Training (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Demonstration of Economic Development Program for Harlem (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Development of Program Planning Instrument at MFY (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Educationally Supportive Group Services Program (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Employee Relations Work in Personnel Departments for Adults (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Enhancing Educational and Vocational Training of Youth in an Israeli Slum (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Establish Field Placements for 100 Graduate Students from all New York (Box 20A)
  - Metropolitan Area Schools of Social Work (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Experimental Laboratory Program (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Experimental Non-graded Primary Program (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Fifth Year Detached Worker Program (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Laboratory Pre-School in Urban Depressed Area (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Neighborhood Manpower Service Center for the Lower East Side (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Police -Community Relations Improvement (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Pre -Adolescent Program (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Programming in Riis Amphitheater (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: School Program Redevelopment and Reorganization (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Small Business Services (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Small Group Program to Increase Learning Capacity and Classroom (Box 20A)
  - Adjustment of Elementary School Children (Box 20A)
  - Proposal: Teaching Assistance in Reading (Box 21)
  - Proposal: Teacher Training Institute for Neighborhood Youth Corps (Box 21)
  - Proposal: Training and Employing Community Heat Inspectors (Box 21)
  - Proposal: Training and Placement of Community Employment Technicians (Box 21)
  - Proposal: Training Non-professional Youth and Adults (Box 21)
  - Proposal: Urban Cooperative Development on Lower East Side (Box 21)
  - Public Service Careers Program (Box 21)
  - Release no. 107 -8 Oct 1964 re Panel of Experts (Box 21)
  - Remedial Education Program (Box 21)
  - Repertory Theatre (Box 21)
  - Report to Board of Directors(Board and Executive Structure} 1 Feb 1965 (Box 21)
  - Resolution adopted by Board of Directors Ee Investigation of MFY (Box 21)
  - Resolution Adopted by Board of Directors 15 Oct 1965 (Box 21)
  - Resolution adopted by Board of Directors -Resignation of James McCarthy (Box 21)
  - Schedule of Meetings (Box 21)
  - Screvane Report -November 1964 (Box 21)
  - Screvane Report -January 1965 (Box 21)
  - Services to Individuals and Families (Box 21)
  - Shriver~ R. Sargent -General (Box 21)
  - Shriver, R. Sargent -Comments on "Consumer Credit Protection Act" (Box 21)
  - Small Business Investment Corporation (Box 22)
  - Social Work Education Center - Correspondence (Box 22)
  - Social Work Education Center – Proposal and Budget (Box 22)
  - Social Work Training Center - Correspondence (Box 22)
  - Social Work Training Center - Proposal and Budget (Box 22)
  - Social Worker – Job Specification (Box 22)
  - Special Committee on Housing – Correspondence (Box 22)
  - Speeches – Bertram M. Beck (Box 22)
  - Staff Development – College (Box 22)
  - Staff Development – Old Age (Box 22)
  - Staff Development – Vista Associate Program (Box 22)
  - Statement by Winslow Carlton – 3 December 1964 (Box 22)
  - Statement by Chairman of the Board and Officers of MFY – 16 August 1964 (Box 22)
  - Statement by Norman Dorsen (Box 22)
  - Statement by Samuel Ganz (Box 22)
  - Statement by Mitchell I. Ginsberg (Box 23)
  - Statement of MFY Staff re Attack on MFY – 14 September 1964 (Box 23)
  - Statement by National Association of Social Workers – 15 November 1964 (Box 23)
  - Statement by Office of Economic Opportunity (Box 23)
  - Summer 1965 – Work program (Box 23)
  - Summer 1966 – Anti-poverty Program (Box 23)
  - Summer 1967 – Subcontracts and Budget (Box 23)
  - Teacher – Helper Newsletter (Box 23)
  - Technical Housing Department (Box 23)
  - Testimony by William F.X. Flynn (Box 23)
  - Testimony by James J. McCarthy (Box 23)
  - "They Want to Make Good" – Job Center of Division of Employment Opportunities (Box 23)